[Music]
good evening everybody i'm nick welcome
back to polar ice creamery
this video
is gonna be a blind comparison so
previously if you've watched any of our
videos have a look at our channel we
made the other version of
this the twists cookie dough twist
um
it went quite well it had
two different color
chocolate chips in it all combined so
they had a green and blue chocolate chip
throughout i didn't manage to make those
i did them independently in color but
the result was pretty decent so we're
gonna try this one i've not tried it as
you can see it's completely sealed
now i've used their ingredients that
they show on their website it's a new
method that's what's in here before we
compare
let's see how we made it
[Music]
so this one is going to start completely
different to most of our other videos
it's water in the pan and to that we're
going to add our sugars so it's dextrose
and just straight table sugar mixed into
the sugar is our stabilizers which is a
guar gum and carrageenan mix that's a 70
30 mix i'll put some details in the
description
dissolve the sugars down and then what
you're going to do is add in your
condensed milk and your egg yolks
keep stirring that nice until it's
combined then finally add in your cocoa
powder as your mix starts coming up to
temperature again to cook the egg yolks
we're looking at something around 65 to
70 degrees
you can then add in your cream and not a
lot of cream going in this so
so it'll be quite interesting to see the
result
once that's ready you can take it off
the heat and put it in a container as
normal pop it in the fridge until it's
ready to churn
[Music]
now for the cookie dough core what we're
going to do is we're going to start with
our room temperature butter really nice
and soft add to that your sugars which
is both brown
and white sugar get that mixed really
nice add in a touch of vanilla extract
and then your golden syrup if you don't
have golden syrup where you are you can
just use corn syrup but not the high
fructose stuff though that's just
disgusting
once that's nicely combined you're going
to add in your cocoa powder and your
heat treated flour this is in the uk
this is plain flour or north america
all-purpose flour to heat treat it you
have to heat it up to 180 degrees for 10
minutes let it cool down completely
otherwise you'll end up melting a
plastic sieve like i did before
then mix it really well and finally add
in your chocolate chips get that nicely
mixed together
rather than put it in any other kind of
container i've put it in a bag so it
cools down nice and quickly in the
fridge
once that's completely cooled you can
mold it into the shape of the core
and then once it's rolled up into a nice
cylinder pop it back in the freezer
so now that your ice cream base has
chilled in the fridge this is probably
going to take three to four hours take
it out and put it in your ice cream
machine and let it churn as normal
just before the end of the churn you can
add in your chocolate chips that are
mixed make sure they're well combined
into the ice cream itself and then start
loading up the tub there's no swirls or
nothing to do here so just fill up your
tub but make sure you leave some space
at the top i'd recommend something
around an inch
because you're going to insert your
chocolate cookie dough core straight
into the middle like this if there's any
space left on the top then just top it
up with your ice cream mix then put the
whole tub in the freezer for a good few
hours just to harden off completely
[Music]
and there we go it's really weird no
milk i've
you know vegan ice creams
i'm used to making those with no milk
but for a dairy based ice cream to not
use milk it's a new one on me
one thing to note is
it was quite thick quite equal you know
quite viscous base
that usually tends to mean a creamier
less icy finish sometimes it means you
end up with a block of ice but you know
by and large this came together really
really well now the
double or double
uh chocolate cookie dough twist is
described as chocolate ice cream with
swirly chocolate cookie dough center and
chocolaty chunks
so
what we're gonna do i think is
get the ice creams out of both of these
tubs
cut them in half and put them on the
plate so we can do a direct comparison
[Music]
there we go both ice creams came out of
the tubs pretty well i had to warm them
up in my hands you can warm them up
under the tap if you wanted to do this
with an ice cream that you make just so
you can see how they compare to the
shops
now
we know
i know
that ben and jerry's use a
what's called a dropper to insert the
cookie dough it's actually quite liquid
in comparison to ours when they do it
and as you can see
it's kind of a bit of a funky
shape ours we've got complete control
over the shape of ours how it's put into
the ice cream
we can obviously create a perfect shape
core
it's nothing detrimental to ben and
jerry's it's just how it's done on a
mass production scale
color wise
i think i think ours is just a little
bit darker
it's icing up because it's
just come out and freeze over i think
it's a little bit darker cookie dough
slightly different color i'd say ours is
a bit more traditional chocolate color
that one's quite dark
but i don't know what cocoa powder they
use i can't find out there's so many
different cocoa powders trying to track
it down it's just going to be a
nightmare so
use whatever cocoa powder you like taste
of
i think
pound for pound though
i'm pretty happy with that
my wife has just pointed out that
there's more chocolate chips in
ours
i can't see oh i can see one
there's a chocolate chip there
but you know
let's try some of each and see how we
got on
[Music]
i'm really happy with ours the taste of
the ice cream is really good now i'm
really impressed with this style or this
method of making
it's super super creamy
it's you know that there's no
iciness the texture is super smooth
really really nice
obviously i've used
a cocoa powder that we've used before
they seem to only use fat reduced cocoa
powder in their recipes so that's what
we've used here i think the one the
design one that i used was 12
but um
trying to find out again what they use
is very difficult it scoops really well
it's really smooth it's kind of
bordering on on gelato kind of texture
and something to note is that the mix or
the recipe in the description below
makes about 700 to 750
milliliter base mixed and that's
actually under
the minimum requirement for our machine
so
i'm going to say we probably didn't get
quite as much overrun as we should do
but you know most people don't have
machines quite this big at home they
have much smaller ones and in which case
that size would do you really well
with that with the com with the
chocolate chips and the cookie dough
you're going to get a solid one liter or
two
ml tubs
the cookie dough
ben and joe's cookie dough is
how do i put this politely
it's crap it's it's
powdery
sugar
that's that's what you're getting
it it disintegrates in your mouth
and the granules of sugar that you're
eating it's really off-putting it's
always been like that i don't understand
why
it's that bad and a lot of people know
on their websites also say that the same
thing that the cookie dough is is pretty
poor
and also something knows you don't get a
huge amount of cookie dough
cork in it you know as you can see we
took that little bit out that fell out
it's um
yeah
not overly impressed with the cookie
dough kind of everything
but
the ice cream
itself is a little bit low on flavor not
particularly strong chocolate flavor
again we are in control of what we're
making here so you can use any cocoa
powder you like strong flavored weak
flavoured whatever suits you
so i'm not surprised i prefer mine
because i've made it using ingredients
that i like but ultimately what we've
been able to do here is recreate this
flavor just much better so i hope you've
enjoyed this
direct comparison or blind comparison
for the ben jerry's double chocolate
cookie dough twist and our own version
it's probably going to be a couple of
weeks before we put our next video out
we're now we're selling our ice cream
finding it difficult to find the time to
do a video every week you know we've got
family to spend time with as well
so
in between those times rather than do
full videos we're going to do some
shorter videos things you know like
prepping our add-ins for our retail ice
cream as well so there's still lots of
content to watch hope you stick around
thanks very much for liking and
subscribing and we'll see you next time
[Music]
you